

CAREER PROFILE

After graduating with a degree in Environmental Science, I took some time to work and find a path that was right for me. This lead me to the GIS Certificate program at the University of Wisconsin Madison. Environmental issues were not the only problems I learned to apply GIS solutions for. My courses gave me exponentially more skills for solving other complex problems within many domains. The complexities of environmental systems gave me a sturdy background for looking at intricate problems in almost any sector of business, natural resources, and other sciences. Through working at the Wisconsin State Cartographer's Office, I gained valuable developer skills and was able to apply them in a job setting for two years while taking classes. I seek to continue expanding my experience in GIS, GIS development, and beyond.



EXPERIENCES

GIS Developer

2016-2018

2014-2017

Wisconsin State Cartographer's Office

Investigate and Implement a workflow to process and prepare Landsat data and images obtained from the Amazon S3 Cloud provided by Amazon Web Services for use over large study areas in the state of Wisconsin

Georeference 1930s Aerial Photography for Wisconsin Coastal Bordner Survey Explorer application. Before georeferencing, automated sorting, croping, and photomerging scripts were used to prepare images based on townships. After georeferencing, images were mosaicked and clipped by county to then be tiled seemlessly for the coastal counties of Wisconsin. (https://maps.sco.wisc.edu/BordnerCoastal)

Maintain the Public Land Survey System PostgresSQL database and webmap applications as well as the Control Finder applications on the SCO website.

GIS Student 2016-2018

University of Wisconsin Madison

COURSES: Intro to Remote Sensing
Intro to GIS Intro to Geocomputing

Intro to Cartography Graphic Design and Cartography
Advanced Quantitative Methods Spatial Web/Mobile Programming

GIS Capstone:

MAPPING EVAPOTRANSPIRATION
WITH LANDSAT8 IN THE METRIC MODEL
OVER LARGE STUDY AREAS

High School Hockey and Softball Coach

Baraboo High School, Wisconsin

Apply knowledge from years of playing to coach JV and Varsity players

Assistant Editor for About Place Journal 2015-2016

Black Earth Institute, Wisconsin

Review and asses submissions via submittable. Help maintain database of submitters and donors as well as assist in website layout management for About Place Journal and Black Earth Institute.



Dawson Bancroft-Short GIS Developer/Analyst



dawsonbancroftshort@gmail.com



608-370-1687

EDUCATION

GIS Certificate
University of Wisconsin Madison
2016-2018

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Science Chatham University 2008-2013

Languages

English (Native)
Spanish Basic (3 years)
Swahili Basic (3 years)

Interests

Hockey
Drumming
Cooking
Gardening
Sailing



SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

Soft Skills

Teaching, Training, Coaching

Organization

Motivation & Initiative

Teamwork & Communication

Observant & Detail Oriented

Customer Service & Ability to Communicate With Diverse Population

Hard Skills

ArcGIS, QGIS, & OSGEO

Carto & Mapbox Studio

Python & SQL

Amazon Web Services (AWS)

MODFLOW with FREEWAT

HTML, CSS, 8 JS

Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop

Data Management

For more information and a full portfolio, please visit:

myatlas.github.io

References:

Available Upon Request

Available Upon Request

Available Upon Request